# Johnny Casares

LinkedIn | GitHub

## **Projects**

#### What the Bird doing **?** (Python, APIs: eBird, XenoCanto, Google)

**Spring 2023** 

Developed a user-friendly Streamlit web app displaying comprehensive bird data from eBird API, integrated with XenoCanto API for bird sounds and Google API for bird images. Focused on adhering to Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) principles for a seamless user experience

### Valorant Match Outcome ML Model (Python, Power Automate)

**Summer 2023** 

Utilized web scraping to collect and evaluate data from 300+ matches. Developed a K-Nearest Neighbor (KNN) ML model for predicting match outcomes with high accuracy and F1-score. Applicable to game development, esports analytics, team management, and esports betting

### My Team Manager (Flutter, Firebase)

Summer 202

Designed and developed "My Team Manager" app with Flutter and Firebase for seamless user authentication and profile management. Provides soccer enthusiasts with an effective platform for creating and organizing teams, choosing positions, and team building

#### Education

## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

2020-2023

- Florida International University (FIU), Miami, FL
- Relevant Coursework: Machine Learning, AI, Statistics for CS, Operating Systems, Software Engineering, Mobile App Development, Human Computer Interaction, Systems Programming
- Involvement: UPE Ignite member, Google DSC member, Codepath member, Shellhacks (2021, 2022), Flutter Puzzle Hack 2022, and Women in CS member

## Work Experience

#### **Mobile App Developer**

June 2022 – Present

- Implement features and enhancements based on user feedback and product owner requests
- Collaborate with product owner to translate requirements into technical specifications

## **Teacher Assistant for Programming 1**

May 2022 – Summer 2023

- Provide educational support to reinforce problem solving skills in students
- Give feedback to professor and students on students' performance

#### **UPE Ignite Remote Volunteer Teacher Internship, Team Lead**

January 2021 – May 2021

- Managed the 3-person team by effectively communicating and distributing workload
- Used Google CS First Curriculum to introduce middle school students to programming
- Analyzed performance and interest of students to plan lessons for the following session

#### Miami-Dade County Public Schools, IT Intern

Summer 2018 and Summer 2019

- Assisted IT Technicians track, analyze, fix, and replace devices in 5 schools around Miami
- Set up and organized school settings for over 100 classrooms to ensure a smooth start

### Skills

Technical: App development (Java, Flutter, Python), IDEs: Android Studio, IntelliJ, VS Code

Languages: Java, Dart (Flutter), Python, C Languages: Fluent in English and Spanish